ABOUT ME

In my career, I have always been passionate about creating beautiful experiences. In the beginning, my focus was primarily on ensuring that the product I was building was a beautiful experience for users. As I progressed in my career, I became more and more interested in engineering and architecture, and ensuring that the codebase is as beautiful to work with as the app is to use. More recently, I have started to realise that a lot of my professional interest is now in ensuring the people I work with have a beautiful environment in which to work.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Android developer Apr 2021–present (contract)

Dovetail (Afterpay)

I joined Dovetail on a contract to work with their client, Afterpay, to help build a new native version of their Android app. This role is primarily technical and has been an interesting challenge, as the codebase was very new upon my joining and was architected in a uniquely modular way. I have tried to aid the team to adopt new processes that could improve our efficiency and quality, but unfortunately due to the nature of the relationship between Dovetail and Afterpay, I have not been able to have as much impact in this domain as I would like.

- Built several new custom UI components.
- Implemented functionality for several features across the app.
- Contributed to and led architectural discussions and decisions within the team.
- Requirements gathering and high-level planning for a major piece of work.

Senior Android developer May 2020–Mar 2021 (contract)

Westpac

I joined Westpac initially to help get the Android app into a good state ready to be handed over to an Auckland-based team, but also contributed to several features and made other improvements in my time. The team makeup and processes changed several times in my time at the company; I also made significant contribution to improving the team processes and overall happiness of the people in the team. I was operating as *de facto* tech lead for the Android practice in my last few months.

- Contributed the bulk of development to the "Manage devices" feature, and led development on the "Password reset" feature.
- Helped to interview and hire new Android developers.
- Mentored and upskilled new Android developers.
- Introduced better and more documentation and processes across the Android practice.
- Introduced standardized architecture across the Android codebase.
- Helped to improve the team's processes (for example, by introducing definitions of done and improving story writing practices).

Senior Android developer *Apr 2019–Oct 2019 (contract)*

Alphero

A six month contract which gave me the opportunity to work with many different clients on many different projects. Working on so many projects in a short space of time helped me improve my ability to quickly pick up and learn new codebases (which vary in architecture, age, and technologies), as well as deliver features to deadlines. It also helped me learn how to work with different clients, and adapt to their varying processes.

- Worked primarily individually to do bug fixes and minor improvements to a range of apps, including Metservice, RNZ, Nova Energy, and more.
- Responsible for adding new functionality to an app used internally at a government department.
- Worked alongside an iOS developer to understand and implement a new advertising framework for TVNZ OnDemand (for both mobile devices and Android TV).
- Worked on a number of research projects, including building a prototype machine learning-based recommendation engine, and a prototype Actions on Google (i.e. Google Assistant) app.

Senior Android developer Feb 2017-Apr 2019

Trade Me

My primary responsibility was development on the highly-complex main Trade Me app.

- Feature development using an in-house MVVM-based architecture.
- Unit testing, code reviews, and general practice improvement.
- Responsible for helping size and prioritise work.
- Aided in interviewing candidates for roles in the team.
- Provided input into product ideation and helping to solve the problems we faced.
- Responsible for evangelising mobile across a traditionally-desktop focused company.
- Mentoring of both a newly-hired junior Android developer, and another internal person interested in becoming a developer.
- Involved in reviewing proposed API changes to ensure backwards compatibility and provide suggestions from a mobile-consumer point of view.

Android developer Apr 2016–Dec 2016

Leaping Tiger

Leaping Tiger was a small local startup with a product designed to connect gamers to their local communities. I was the sole Android developer at the company, and not only was responsible for building the app from a WebView to a fully featured native app, but also for much of the UI design and some development of the Rails API. Additionally, I brought my experience as a Squad Master to help the team adopt an Agile approach and upskill in these practices.

Android developer Dec 2012-Apr 2016

Trade Me

I initially started at Trade Me as an intern through the Summer of Tech programme, continuing on part-time as I went back to uni to do my Masters' degree, and eventually joining the team on a full-time basis upon completion. Due to my interest in improving team process (and a belief that our team could be operating more efficiently), I later volunteered to take on the squad master role, which involved helping our team continually improve its Agile development processes.

OTHER PROJECTS AND EXPERIENCE

- Occasional freelance Android development for **Hnry**, including: making improvements
 to the architecture of their simple WebView-based app to make it more testable;
 setting up a CI/CD pipeline for ease of testing; writing documentation to make
 maintenance of the codebase easier for them.
- A personal side project called **Fiity** which has involved building a reasonably complex Android app and backend Firebase data storage and cloud services.
- Occasional blogger and public speaker

ANDROID SKILLS TOOLKIT

- Development using both Kotlin (preferred) and Java
- Unit testing with libraries such as Mockito
- Experience with libraries including RxJava, Dagger, Koin, Retrofit/OkHttp,
- Android Jetpack (Navigation/Lifecycle/Room)
- Experience with building Firebase backend
- Experience with MVP and MVVM design patterns
- Some experience with setting up CI/CD pipelines

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering 2013–2014

Victoria University of Wellington

Graduated with Merit. Received Masters by Thesis scholarship. My thesis investigated how improved experiences could be achieved with alternative keyboards and text input methods.

Bachelor of Engineering 2009-2012

Victoria University of Wellington

Graduated with First Class Honours. Included on Dean's List for academic excellence in 2012.